Yahor Sheka

Java Software Engineer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/egorsheka

SUMMARY

4+ years of hands-on experience in Software Development, Java, E-Commerce, Travel, Fintech.

Responsibilities: solution design and development, maintenance, performance optimization, code review and refactoring, mentoring.

Communication with client, planning, reporting.

Strengths: ability to self organize and focus on work, attentive to detail, responsible and reliable, optimistic, good communication skills, team player, work with focus on success.

EXPERIENCE

GP Solutions, Warsaw — Java Software Engineer

JUNE 2023 - NOW

Travel. PropertyVIEW – content monitoring and distribution management software offering the hospitality industry solutions to streamline and optimize content all in one place. Transit from crafting to assembly line model. **Achievements:** Successfully redesigned and implemented the 'crowdsourcing marketplace' model. Implemented statistical methods algorithms with multithreading, and developed an internal database with denormalization support.

Sam Solutions, Minsk — Java Software Engineer

JANUARY 2022 - MAY 2023

E-commerce B2B, B2C. Komus – largest stationery retailer in CIS countries. Transformation of monolithic platform to microservices architecture. Migration to new version, developing new features.

Achievements: Implemented a data-intensive microservice for generating identifiers. Participated in the development of a platform renovation solution involving two distinct applications with different versions. Developed and implemented segmentation logic to manage traffic between the two systems.

DECEMBER 2020 - DECEMBER 2021

Fintech. Kazakhstan tax application. Orchestrated service communication via SOAP and message brokers, developed RESTful APIs, designed and implemented data validation mechanismsa for a financial reporting system.

MARCH 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

E-commerce B2C. MTS – telecommunications company from Serbia. Developed core functionality for e-commerce platform, including product display pages (PDP), product detail pages (PDC), shopping cart, cart sharing, and add-ons.

EDUCATION

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Specialist, Information Systems and Technologies (in economy) Warsaw, Poland +48 571 578 902 egorsheka@gmail.com

SKILLS

Java 7-17

SAP Customer Experience

Spring Framework, Boot, MVC, Data, Security, Integration, Cloud Vaadin

Monolithic/Microservices

REST, OpenAPI, gRPC

JPA, Hibernate

JMS, AMQP, RabbitMQ, Kafka

Tomcat, Jetty, Nginx

SQL, Oracle DB, MySQL, PostgreSQL

MongoDB, Redis, Liquibase

Unit/integration testing, TDD, JUnit, Mockito, Selenium JS, jQuery, Vue.js

Ant, Maven, Gradle

Git

CI/CD, Jenkins, GitLab, Docker, ELK, Grafana Linux, Python, Groovy, UML JIRA, Confluence

LANGUAGES

English(Intermediate)

Russian/Belorussian(Native)